# JOHN BURGESON

jburgeson@gmail.com

**№**847-757-6169

New York

im linkedin.com/in/jburgeson

#### **SUMMARY**

Agile and Interdisciplinary manager with 7+ years experience leveraging strengths in project management, decision support analysis, strategic planning, business development and web development. In it to collaborate with smart people on solutions to knotty problems while simultaneously making things look a bit nicer.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Blocbox (blocbox.co)

2014 - Present

## Co Founder & Head of Product

Brooklyn, NY

- · Launched marketplace that enables people working from home to receive packages and perform tasks for neighbors
- Manage day-to-day operations of the team, including product strategy, product development, logistics and marketing
- Designed and developed the front-end of the beta platform, integrating social commerce UI/UX concepts and features

Booz Allen Hamilton

2008 - 2011

## Associate, Advanced Analytics Business Unit

McLean, VA

- · Led projects on policy and strategy development, risk analysis, and strategic foresight for defense community clients
- Expanded client support: identified unmet client needs, produced white papers, and developed new service offerings
- Promoted from Senior Consultant for contributions to two contract wins with the U.S. Navy

## U.S. Navy, Office of the Chief of Naval Operations (CNO)

2009 - 2011

## Strategic Planning Analyst, Naval Warfare Integration Group (N00X)

Washington, DC

- Provided full-time, on-site, project management and decision support as a Booz Allen consultant
- · Led the production of monthly planning briefs for CNO that analyzed strategic, budgetary, and operational risks
- · Briefed data-driven recommendations to senior leaders that resulted in strategic and program guidance
- Performed data collection, consolidation, analysis and visualization to create compelling narratives

## **Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS)**

2006 - 2008

## Research Assistant, International Security Program

Washington, DC

- Conducted original research on a range of international security issues, including U.S. government national security reform and the impact of future security threats on the demand for defense capabilities
- Contributing author and editor to the 2008 CSIS report, "Facilitating a Dialogue on National Security Priorities"

## U.S. Department of Defense, United States Pacific Command (USPACOM)

2012

Research Intern, Global Peacekeeping Operations Initiative (GPOI)

Camp H.M. Smith, HI

**Independent Graphic and Web Design** 

2007 - Present

## **EDUCATION**

## The Fletcher School, Tufts University

Master of Arts in International Law and Diplomacy • Medford, MA • 2014 Thesis: Improving Foresight for Decision-making: The Emerging Opportunity in the Age of Big Data

#### **HEC Paris**

MBA Exchange - Jouy-en-Josas, France - 2012

## The Colorado College

Bachelor of Arts, Major: International Political Economy - Colorado Springs, CO - 2005

#### SKILLS